<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>terraform on Massimiliano's Tech Chronicles</title><link>https://ilmax.github.io/site/tags/terraform/</link><description>Recent content in terraform on Massimiliano's Tech Chronicles</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 14:44:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ilmax.github.io/site/tags/terraform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Terraform Tips &amp; Tricks: Managing Large-Scale Azure Resource Imports</title><link>https://ilmax.github.io/site/posts/import-many-terraform/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 14:44:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ilmax.github.io/site/posts/import-many-terraform/</guid><description>This post describes my journey to import several hundred Azure resources in Terraform. Before digging into the what and the how let me give you a brief description of our environment&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure.
In my current company, we manage many Azure resources for each environment and we have a few of them (DEV, TEST, etc.). Every environment looks pretty much the same and it mostly differs by product SKUs, database sizes, etc.</description></item><item><title>Create Azure Container Apps with terraform</title><link>https://ilmax.github.io/site/posts/aca-terraform/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 10:04:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ilmax.github.io/site/posts/aca-terraform/</guid><description>Microsoft announced at Microsoft Build that Azure Container Apps are now generally available (GA).
If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar with Azure Container Apps (ACA) I suggest you to go and check out the documentation here.
Fully managed serverless container service for building and deploying modern apps at scale
This is how Microsoft itself markets the product.
I think it&amp;rsquo;s a very interesting platform and it offers some of the benefits of Kubernetes, abstracting a lot of concepts and complexity.</description></item><item><title>Using Managed Identity with Azure WebJobs and Service Bus</title><link>https://ilmax.github.io/site/posts/servicebus-managed-identity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 10:01:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ilmax.github.io/site/posts/servicebus-managed-identity/</guid><description>Managed Service Identity (or MSI for short) allows Azure resources to connect to Azure services that supports AD authentication (see the full list here) without using secrets. This is extremely useful because handling secrets the proper way it&amp;rsquo;s far from easy.
How MSI works is beyond the scope of the article and you can find more information here, but in a nutshell:
You create a service principal object and an application in Azure AD to represents your service (this is done automatically when turning on managed identity) You grant some permissions to access the downstream service it needs to communicate to You configure the authentication to the downstream service to be done via MSI In my case, I have a WebJob that processes messages via a ServiceBus queue, so I granted the service principal a permission to read from the queue using the built in Azure Service Bus Data Receiver role.</description></item><item><title>Implement Azure AD Workload Identity on AKS with terraform</title><link>https://ilmax.github.io/site/posts/azwi-k8s/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 09:55:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ilmax.github.io/site/posts/azwi-k8s/</guid><description>Azure makes it very easy to create managed identities for a variety of services (e.g. Azure Functions, App Services, Logic Apps&amp;hellip;), but when we want to implement it for Azure Kubernetes Service, things gets just a bit more complicated.
First of all we have few options to choose from:
AAD Pod Identity (deprecated) Azure AD Workload Identity What we discuss in this post, azwi for brevity. Both solutions aims to associate a pod with an identity in Azure Active Directory so we can grant this identity permissions to access another resource (i.</description></item><item><title>Configure secret-less connection from App Services to Azure Sql via terraform</title><link>https://ilmax.github.io/site/posts/azure-sql-secret-less-conn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 18:17:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ilmax.github.io/site/posts/azure-sql-secret-less-conn/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since we can connect App services to Azure Sql in a secret-less fashion, using managed service identity (MSI for brevity from now onwards).
The configuration is a bit more complicated than connecting to other Azure services e.g. Azure Storage Account because it involves running some queries on the Azure Sql database in order to create the user and grant them the required privileges, for more info see the tutorial here.</description></item><item><title>Poor mans App services deployment slot auto-swap for Linux with GitHub Actions</title><link>https://ilmax.github.io/site/posts/poor-man-linux-swap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 18:14:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ilmax.github.io/site/posts/poor-man-linux-swap/</guid><description>Nowadays App Service deployment has became quite straight forward. Since support for running Docker containers was added to the platform, this has become my preferred way of deploying and running code in production.
One way to deploy a Docker container to an App Service is taking advantage of an Azure Container Registry (henceforth referred to as ACR), the process looks like this:
Ahead of time:
Configure the App Service to pull the image from your ACR During continuous delivery build:</description></item></channel></rss>