<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>github on Massimiliano's Tech Chronicles</title><link>https://ilmax.github.io/site/tags/github/</link><description>Recent content in github on Massimiliano's Tech Chronicles</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 10:12:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ilmax.github.io/site/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Zero downtime deployment with Azure Container Apps and Github Actions - Part 1</title><link>https://ilmax.github.io/site/posts/aca-zero-downtime-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 10:12:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ilmax.github.io/site/posts/aca-zero-downtime-1/</guid><description>Introduction As you may know, Azure Container Apps went out of preview during Microsoft Build in late May this year. Azure Container Apps is a very interesting service that runs on top of Kubernetes adding some additional powerful capabilities in a simple and covinient way. Some of these capabilities are:
Built in support for Keda autoscalers Built in support for Dapr components Ability to scale to zero There&amp;rsquo;s a lot more to it, you can dig deeper on the official Microsoft documentation here</description></item><item><title>Poor mans App services deployment slot auto-swap for Linux with GitHub Actions</title><link>https://ilmax.github.io/site/posts/poor-man-linux-swap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 18:14:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ilmax.github.io/site/posts/poor-man-linux-swap/</guid><description>Nowadays App Service deployment has became quite straight forward. Since support for running Docker containers was added to the platform, this has become my preferred way of deploying and running code in production.
One way to deploy a Docker container to an App Service is taking advantage of an Azure Container Registry (henceforth referred to as ACR), the process looks like this:
Ahead of time:
Configure the App Service to pull the image from your ACR During continuous delivery build:</description></item></channel></rss>